<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>GamertechAU</title>
    <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com" />
    <updated>2025-03-17T14:30:50+11:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>GamertechAU</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.gamertechau.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/44/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-03-17T14:23:00+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/44/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza.webp" alt="Game poster for Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii showing a Japanese man in a pirate coat, eyepatch and tricorne hat holding 2 cutlasses" />
                    Details Name Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii Completed on 2025-03-17&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/44/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii showing a Japanese man in a pirate coat, eyepatch and tricorne hat holding 2 cutlasses" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 48.0625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.0625px;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.0625px;">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">2025-03-17</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.0625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.0625px;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.0625px;">SEGA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii is already my Game of the Year. Seriously, it's that good. If you like the Yakuza/Like a Dragon series, then get it. It's clear that the devs were allowed to have fun with it and it shows.</p>
<p>This is going to be tricky to explain without spoilers as there's so much unique content, all with RGG's staple well-balanced humour let off the leash a little to match the main character's wild personality, but I'll do my best!</p>
<p>Pirate Majima is a canon spin-off based after the events of LAD: Infinite Wealth (yes this game does have spoilers for IW, so play that first), you play long-time character Goro Majima who washes up on the beach of a tiny Hawaiian island having lost his memory (but not his booty kicking skills).</p>
<p>Through a traditionally chaotic series of events, Majima takes command of a pirate sailing ship and explores Hawaii in the search for fun, treasure and (eventually) his memories.</p>
<p>As you progress, you unlock crop and animal farming for obtaining cooking ingredients, ship upgrades, crew and customisation (more available from DLC), seemingly every minigame from previous Yakuza games plus new ones, music that you can play on your phone while sailing around and equipment that improves Majima's personal stats for on-foot combat.</p>
<p>While sailing, you'll encounter hostile ships and battle them for loot and crew xp and is a extremely well designed system. Entering combat is seamless, targeting requires you to pay attention to the waves that bob your ship around as well as other environmental factors. You can also swap to deck view and explore the deck on foot, revive fallen comrades, or repel boarders.</p>
<p>Exploring on foot, you have the staple Yakuza real-time combat, not turn-based as in recent Like a Dragon games. With two stances to choose from, each focused on single-target or group combat and lots of skill upgrades purchasable using cash and reputation earned throughout the play through.</p>
<p>On day one release, the game ran perfectly out of the box with no crashes, stutters, performance issues etc. It was also extremely well optimised so didn't need upscaling/fake frames to get a playable frame rate. The audio was also excellent. RGG certainly put a lot of effort into this spin-off and it has me really looking forward to Project Century which looks to be an entirely new IP.</p>
<p>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii is a seriously well-made game and if you're a fan of the series, is 100% a buy. Play through time with not-quite 100%'ing the game came to 47.7 hours.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DREDGE</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/dredge/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/dredge/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/43/DREDGE.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-02-20T15:10:41+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/43/DREDGE.webp" alt="Game poster for DREDGE showing a fishing boat a lighthouse mutated fish under the water" />
                    Details Name DREDGE Completed on 2025-02-20 Developers Black Salt Games Publishers Team&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/43/DREDGE.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for DREDGE showing a fishing boat a lighthouse mutated fish under the water" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">DREDGE</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Black Salt Games</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Team 17</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>An extremely well-made game. Played with the Pale Reach and Iron Rig DLC.</p>
<p>In DREDGE, you play a fisherman who accepted a job as an angler for a remote island chain. A nice peaceful job...Except this is a Lovecraft game.</p>
<p>Putter around the ocean fishing up a huge (230) range of fish in different biomes to sell for income or to fill special orders, but be back before sundown as these fish bite back. There's a ton of hidden quests hidden around the map, plenty of NPC's to talk to with stories, most of whom need your help to find various fish and items.</p>
<p>As you explore you find or unlock upgrades to your boat, including faster, more redundant motors (you'll need em), specialised fishing equipment that can operate in more areas, more powerful lights, more cargo space, etc. You don't need all of them to complete the game, but you will need a lot.</p>
<p>You'll also find new hungry things interested in you (BIG goober fish), and natural events that don't mix well with your boat such as water spouts. Each biome has its own hazards and all of them increase your stress, which as it gets higher seems to attract more things to you.</p>
<p>As the story progresses, you'll learn about and potentially encounter a number of cosmic horrors with plenty of Lovecraft-inspired lore to find.</p>
<p>DREDGE ran perfectly with no noticeable issues and has a Platinum rating on ProtonDB. The audio was excellent and heightened the immersion of the game and the art style fit the mood perfectly. The devs put a lot of effort into it.</p>
<p>Highly recommend giving this a go. The DLC if you get them are best played from the early-mid game rather than saving until the end to keep it balanced. Obtained the base game from an Epic freebie.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Slime Rancher</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/slime-rancher/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/slime-rancher/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/42/SlimeRancher.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-02-14T16:27:26+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/42/SlimeRancher.webp" alt="Game poster for Slime Rancher showing colourful slimes, a flying chicken and a girl with cyan hair holding a sci-fi cannon" />
                    Details Name Slime Rancher Completed on 2025-02-14 Developers Monomi Park Publishers Monomi&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/42/SlimeRancher.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Slime Rancher showing colourful slimes, a flying chicken and a girl with cyan hair holding a sci-fi cannon" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Slime Rancher</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-02-14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Monomi Park</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Monomi Park</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>After playing Wolfenstein, this felt like a nice, chill game to veg out on.</p>
<p>Slime Rancher is a fun exploration/adventure game based in the Far, Far Range, an area on a planet 1,000 light years away from Earth. As you explore you can collect different slimes, bring them back to your ranch and keep them in corrals, feeding and family-friendly breeding them to create hybrids. You then collect their 'plorts' and sell them on the market. Other uses open up as you progress.</p>
<p>It's a sandbox game, so the objective is simply to progress your ranch and earn money while collecting limited lore scattered around the map. There are minor threats in game from the environment as well as some hostile slimes, but they don't really provide a challenge, more to add a bit to the 'life' as you explore.</p>
<p>The player gets free reign to build up their ranch as they see fit and can eventually add cosmetics to their slimes (with a DLC adding additional cosmetics). There's multiple distinct areas to unlock to expand your ranch that favour specific types of slimes and eventual automation.</p>
<p>The automation relies on drones you can research and construct then give them simple commands to auto-collect plorts, feed the slimes etc. In my opinion they could've been improved though. They only have enough fuel for one day of work, so each day you have to travel across your large farm to splash each drone base with water, or your slimes starve and riot, escaping their pens and creating chaos on the ranch.</p>
<p>One unfortunate point was the game contains one of the most restrictive stamina systems I've ever seen. Even with your stamina limit fully upgraded, you run out within seconds and as the game relies a lot on platforming using both running and a very anaemic jetpack that both rapidly consume it, you regularly have to stand still and wait for your energy to recharge before you can continue. Stamina systems are designed to slow the player down so the game lasts longer, but there was no actual need for it in Slime Rancher due to the plentiful sandbox content and is just a painful annoyance. There were mods that affect it on Nexus, but none of them seem to function any more unfortunately.</p>
<p>Performance, audio and art were all on point, with the game running perfectly with no stutters or frame drops.</p>
<p>Overall, I recommend Slime Rancher for a chill game session however the stamina issue really was extremely painful, so keep that in mind. Hopefully Slime Rancher 2 improves on it dramatically.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Wolfenstein: The New Order</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/wolfenstein-the-new-order/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/wolfenstein-the-new-order/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/41/WolfensteinTheNewOrder.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-02-05T17:19:13+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/41/WolfensteinTheNewOrder.webp" alt="Game poster of Wolfenstein: The New Order showing dark armoured figures against a bright red background" />
                    Details Name Wolfenstein: The New Order Completed on 2025-02-05 Developers MachineGames Publishers&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/41/WolfensteinTheNewOrder.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Wolfenstein: The New Order showing dark armoured figures against a bright red background" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Wolfenstein: The New Order</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-02-05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">MachineGames</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Bethesda Softworks</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Felt like playing this for...no particular reason. For younger viewers this is a mature-rated game with lots of dark scenes so keep that in mind.</p>
<p>In an alternate 1946, you play William Blazkowicz, a US operative sent in to eliminate a mad scientist powering the bad guy regime by any means necessary. In an unfortunate series of events, you're seriously injured and taken out of the fight for 14 years. Long enough for the baddies to take over the world.</p>
<p>Finally recovered in 1960, your objective is to find any remaining resistance and fight back against the oppressors utilising a variety of firearms and firearm-adjacent weaponry. Also knives. There's lots of sharp objects used in this game. Not always in ways you want.</p>
<p>The story is excellent and takes you to multiple countries, the playable maps while simpler in layout than OG Wolfenstein easily puts modern AAA(A) map design to shame with multiple routes to choose from including the requisite sneaky-boi paths and verticality regularly comes into play. As Star Wars taught us, the high ground matters. There's also plenty of secrets and collectables should you explore.</p>
<p>During the playthrough, you encounter a range of characters including resistance members, civilians, victims of the regime as well as really easy-to-hate members of said regime. The voice acting is excellent and were well-cast in my opinion.</p>
<p>One annoying design choice was that the game consistently takes half your weapons and almost all of your ammunition at the start of each mission, even ones Will knows about well in advance and has plenty of time to prepare. There's plenty of ammo all over of course, however it does seem a bit of a weird choice that he'd knowingly go into battle with a single mag.</p>
<p>The graphics were great, however there was a pretty extreme depth-of-field layer that can't be turned off without using the console, and it's noticeable why that is, as asset pop-in is extremely obvious when disabled and looking around. Unfortunately it's a shortcoming that does detract from the experience, though at least in more open maps, the pop-in isn't really noticeable. It's earned a Platinum rating on ProtonDB.</p>
<p>If you're into complex FPS shooter games with solid stories (and over the age rating), I highly recommend giving Wolfenstein: The New Order a go. Got around 9.5 hours of playtime on stream.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Yakuza 3 Remastered</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-3-remastered/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-3-remastered/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/40/Yakuza3Remastered.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-01-31T18:25:56+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/40/Yakuza3Remastered.webp" alt="Game poster of Yakuza 3 Remastered showing a man in a white suit with red shirt looking upwards and a tall building in the background" />
                    Details Name Yakuza 3 Remastered Completed on 2025-01-31 Developers Ryu Ga Gotoku&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/40/Yakuza3Remastered.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Yakuza 3 Remastered showing a man in a white suit with red shirt looking upwards and a tall building in the background" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Yakuza 3 Remastered</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">SEGA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Up front, Yakuza 3 is a remaster and port of the original 2009 PS3 game, it's not a remake like Yakuza Kiwami 1 &amp; 2, which means it's lacking a lot of quality of life improvements players would've gotten used to. It can be a bit of a shock to the system.</p>
<p>Putting that aside, the story is of course up to RGG's excellent standard. A bit darker than the story in 0-2 it still has the depth and feels players know and love. Continuing off the story of Yakuza 2, we find Kiryu retired in Okinawa, Japan running an orphanage. It's a peaceful life until the Fire Na...uh... Yakuza attack.</p>
<p>Kiryu then gets called out of retirement and is immediately back to punching people in the search for some peace and quiet. During the playthrough, you meet a lot of old friends, plus new ones. Everyone's a little older with new stories and a ton of substories, which are back to their usual lengths and depth compared to the much shorter ones in 2.</p>
<p>Combat is simultaneously simpler and more complex. Enemies actually block or dodge, and have no trouble landing the hurt. The AI of Gun-wielding enemies is extremely limited. Generally they just stand there harmlessly unless you give them a long enough chance to do something. Using heat actions or grabs can be a bit painful as they're very picky about where you need to stand, how long you need to stand still and the option often vanishes before the enemy even starts moving out of the way.</p>
<p>The lack of QoL features in this older game is highly noticeable, though thankfully doesn't detract from the story. You can't sprint outside of the chase minigame unlike previous games which is definitely noticeable as you have to run across town regularly. You can only order one thing at a time at restaurants/cafes/bars etc which makes it extremely slow if you're trying to complete the 'eat everything' achievements or heal a lot of health. The camera control is pretty annoying moving in tight spaces and especially combat. Inventory is back to limited slots and fills up extremely quickly.</p>
<p>The game looks solid for the PS3 era and ran smoothly with no performance issues.</p>
<p>If you're a fan of the Yakuza series, I highly recommend giving Yakuza 3 a go. Hopefully it'll get a Kiwami remake eventually, though at the time of writing, RGG's busy with Pirate Majima and Project Century, so might be a while.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cat Detective Albert Wilde</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/cat-detective-albert-wilde/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/cat-detective-albert-wilde/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/39/CatDetectiveAlbertWilde.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-01-27T17:09:21+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/39/CatDetectiveAlbertWilde.webp" alt="Game poster of Cat Detective Albert Wilde with an anthropomorphic cat kneeling in front of a yellow background" />
                    Details Name Cat Detective Albert Wilde Completed on 2025-01-27 Developers beyondthosehills Publishers&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/39/CatDetectiveAlbertWilde.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Cat Detective Albert Wilde with an anthropomorphic cat kneeling in front of a yellow background" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Cat Detective Albert Wilde</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-01-27</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">beyondthosehills</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">beyondthosehills</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Cat Detective Albert Wilde was a fun and unique detective game. Well worth playing.</p>
<p>You play Albert Wilde, a broke feline private investigator in a noir prohibition-era US world of anthropomorphic animals who, in an effort to get a little scratch, stumbles on a big case that leads you around the city engaging with multiple interesting characters.</p>
<p>Upfront, the game isn't intended to be a brain-melting investigation. The game focuses on the story and dry humour, so the investigative part of it is pretty simple. From their Steam page, the devs describe it as "...something between a walking simulator and an interactive novel, with a strong emphasis on comedy".</p>
<p>The game is fairly linear. You can freely explore unlocked areas, however you can't progress with the story until you find all the key items or dialogue in that stage and it's extremely difficult to get lost. If you do, there's an effective journal in the form of actual notes written by Albert to point you where you need to go.</p>
<p>It is a fairly short game. The devs state 6-7 hours, it took me 5.5 with talking to chat mixed in. Tech-wise it ran perfectly. One gripe is the game settings are only available after starting a new game and progressing past a reasonably loud opening cutscene with all the volume bars set default to 100%. Not ideal for a stream or headphones users. Settings should be available immediately, and volume should default to ~50% to allow players to adjust it without being deafened. It leaves an impression.</p>
<p>Overall I enjoyed the play through and recommend checking it out.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contraband Police</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/contraband-police/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/contraband-police/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/38/ContrabandPolice.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-01-10T16:28:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/38/ContrabandPolice.webp" alt="Game poster of Contraband Police with checkpoint officer in yellow hi-vis holding stop hand up and red baton in front of a red and white checkpoint barrier and officers in the background arresting someone" />
                    Details Name Contraband Police Completed on 2025-01-25 Developers Crazy Rocks Publishers PlayWay&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/38/ContrabandPolice.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Contraband Police with checkpoint officer in yellow hi-vis holding stop hand up and red baton in front of a red and white checkpoint barrier and officers in the background arresting someone" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Contraband Police</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-01-25</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Crazy Rocks</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">PlayWay S.A.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Contraband Police is a fun jank game. The good kind of jank, not the broken mess type.</p>
<p>We played through the campaign mode on stream, working as a very underpaid police commander in charge of seemingly the only border checkpoint into the country ruled by a brutal dictatorship.</p>
<p>The main objective is to inspect vehicles and people coming into the country, ensure their paperwork is legit and they're not smuggling contraband. As you progress, story events happen to the country that affect what you need to look out for such as vehicle defects and forged documents, people coming from countries your bosses don't like and those pesky teachers and journalists...</p>
<p>If that's not enough, you also have to leave your post to transport seized contraband and prisoners across the country to storage or the labour camp where you have a (pretty much guaranteed) chance of getting ambushed by rebels on the road. Have to randomly leave to investigate crimes, intercept contraband drops with infinite waves of enemies (with no backup) etc. Plus you get intermittent rebel raids on the checkpoint forcing you to defend it (with backup).</p>
<p>During the game you can make choices to support the government or the rebels, guiding the story to one of the endings. There's also border crossers with urgent issues such as family emergencies, but almost always have invalid documents/vehicles. Whatever you choose with these, you get a letter either thanking or threatening you. You can choose to let them through, but apparently the government magically inspects their documents after they go through and fine you for it (though still lets them go). If you get anything wrong in an inspection, they fine you an amount depending on your level.</p>
<p>That brings us to the issues. One of them is an annoying bug with the vehicle defect system where you can look all over it and find absolutely everything wrong with it, and the audit says you missed something and fines you for it. For instance, if a vehicle has a front bumper and missing the rear one, you enter one bumper missing and the audit says two, or missing a body panel when the vehicle doesn't have any panels to be missing.</p>
<p>There's four choices of vehicles with different specialities such as speed or cargo transport. The fastest car seemed to have a collision mesh issue especially noticeable on dirt roads which made it really unstable, though not uncontrollable. The other vehicles were more stable.</p>
<p>As well as the campaign, there's two other game modes available, one a sandbox with no time limit, so just freeplay, the other is a challenge mode where you compete against other players on a leaderboard.</p>
<p>Graphically, the game uses the same art style common to PlayWay games. Not the prettiest, but clean and functional. As I progressed through the playthrough, the object culling got far more noticeable to the point I could park in front of the checkpoint's garage and it takes 10+ seconds for the garage to become visible. The collision mesh is there however so if you drive in and miss, you crash into invisible pillars.</p>
<p>Also playing on normal difficulty, I could happily stand still and fire at the enemies with pretty much zero risk of going down. The few times they do manage to hit you, it does almost no damage and heals pretty much instantly so there was no real risk unless you decided to stand on a grenade unfortunately.</p>
<p>Overall, I do recommend Contraband Police. It's a fun game with plenty of content, though the country really should hire more than one police officer. One person managing all this at once is problematic. One campaign playthrough on stream hit 14.2 hours so plenty of content inside.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crysis Remastered</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/crysis-remastered/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/crysis-remastered/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/37/crysis-remastered.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2024-12-13T21:30:15+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/37/crysis-remastered.webp" alt="Crysis Remastered game poster" />
                    Details Name Crysis Remastered Completed on 2024/12/13 Developers Crytek Publishers Crytek Playthrough&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/37/crysis-remastered.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Crysis Remastered game poster" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Crysis Remastered</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2024/12/13</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Crytek</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Crytek</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>The meme game remastered, the Crysis re-release amps up the graphic quality, adds limited raytracing and does it in a pretty smooth-running package. However, there's no shortage of issues and cut corners in this release.</p>
<p>Crysis involves you and your special ops team wearing advanced power armour deploying to a remote island to locate and extract some archaeologists who called for emergency support. Obviously, things don't go as planned and the place goes to heck.</p>
<p>While the game itself runs well and the remaster content is actually remastered, most of the games' settings don't get saved to config. They reset to default every time you restart the game or re-open the settings menu. That includes the ever-present motion blur that studios refuse to get rid of defaulting to enabled.</p>
<p>There's also a popup every time you launch the game warning about raytracing being disabled due to an incompatible driver as instead of checking for supported features which is best practice, or checking for a minimum driver version, they seem to have just whitelisted the latest driver of the time and any before or after that gets a warning. Also, despite the warning, raytracing doesn't actually get disabled, so even that doesn't work.</p>
<p>Add to that, the enemy AI is...terrible. If the enemy aren't shooting at you, they're likely running around in circles, running into a wall or standing completely immobile, refusing to react to your presence until you shoot them. Throw a grenade and they call it out, however instead of running they stand still or cluster towards where it landed.</p>
<p>The enjoyable stealth mechanics from the original Crysis no longer function. If you're not using the suit's cloaking mode, then the enemy sees you. Spend a few minutes slowly walking up behind a rock for a nice ambush location on unsuspecting enemies? Decloak and instantly "There! Shoot him!" with no sound or line of sight. As a stealthy boi, this is pretty game-breaking.</p>
<p>The destructible buildings are also pretty extreme now. A few pistol bullets, or just the player walking into a wall and the building collapses. Violently. No force required. As a bonus, the game sometimes fails to render enemies, meaning you're getting shot by invisible soldiers.</p>
<p>After the first stream of it, I went back and played the OG Crysis. While not perfect of course, none of these problems existed.</p>
<p>While the graphics are pretty as expected (except faces which are noticeably worse), the game itself was not finished before release and contains critical gameplay and design bugs and it's unknown at the time of writing whether they'll be fixed. Right now, I can't recommend purchasing it, especially if you own the original.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cat Quest II</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/cat-quest-ii/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/cat-quest-ii/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/35/CatQuest2.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2024-12-13T17:27:29+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/35/CatQuest2.webp" alt="Cat Quest II game poster" />
                    Details Name Cat Quest II Completed on 2024/12/13 Developers The Gentlebros Publishers&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/35/CatQuest2.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Cat Quest II game poster" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Cat Quest II</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2024/12/13</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">The Gentlebros</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Kepler Interactive</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Cat Quest II is a cute RPG where you play as a cat and dog royalty called to a world to defeat the evil kings and reclaim the land amidst a whole lotta cat/dog puns. It has optional co-op but I played solo for this playthrough.</p>
<p>You pounce around the open world map fighting enemies tag-teaming between the characters. The inactive character fights beside you as a secondary. As you explore you encounter chests holding new gear, or levels for existing gear as well as gold needed for upgrades. NPC's will also have side quests available with fun little stories and of course more puns.</p>
<p>As you play you unlock new armour and weapons all with different buffs to let you build your characters to suit your playstyle. You also can discover many different magic spells, being able to equip four at a time per character. The secondary character will use their spells automatically, though not always effectively.</p>
<p>As above, upgrading your gear and magic takes gold. A lot of it. While you can easily complete the game just from what you earn through normal gameplay, if you're a completionist, maxing out your gear will take a LOT of grinding.</p>
<p>Tech-wise the game ran extremely well with no graphical or performance issues however I had problems with the controller keybinds using my Xbox Elite. B is the interact button, however weirdly it also doubled as the dodge button which isn't intended. Talking to a quest giver causes you to roll away from them, and if you're too far away then the conversation freezes, preventing any further action in the game until you restart it. The game does allow keyboard rebinding, but not controller.</p>
<p>It's a fun game to explore by yourself or with friends. Apparently the controller issue was unusual, so don't expect to encounter it yourself. I got this game as an Epic freebie, however it's available on Steam as well, grab that bundle discount for all three games.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Yakuza Kiwami 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-kiwami-2/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-kiwami-2/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/34/YakuzaKiwami2.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2024-12-10T15:24:09+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/34/YakuzaKiwami2.webp" alt="Yakuza Kiwami 2 game poster" />
                    Details Name Yakuza Kiwami 2 Completed on 2024-12-10 Developers Ryu Ga Gotoku&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/34/YakuzaKiwami2.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Yakuza Kiwami 2 game poster" /></p>
                <h2>Details</h2>
<table class="align-center" style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Yakuza Kiwami 2</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2024-12-10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">SEGA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Playthrough</h2>
<p>Yakuza Kiwami 2 is the third game in our Yakuzathon playthrough and the first in order using the new Dragon engine originally launched in Yakuza 6. It makes a huge difference to the game with lots of quality-of-life improvements over 0 &amp; 1.</p>
<p>The main story is awesome, with deep serious scenes and the usual well-balanced sillyness that Ryu Ga Gotoku are known for. It's believable and fun to engage in, with plenty of time in between arcs to go explore the rest of the game. When you go back to it, you can be sure of taking content right to the face.</p>
<p>While fun, the substories (small side quests) unfortunately felt pretty shallow compared to the previous games. They have good stories, they're just over too soon and lack any sort of impact to the world aside from experience. There just wasn't enough in each to get invested. In 0 &amp; 1, the substories got pretty deep, had characters that 'existed', in 2 once you've done the quest, that's pretty much it.</p>
<p>The usual Yakuza minigames are present including ofc SEGA arcade games. If you enjoy mahjong, SEGA arcades and uh...other unexpected activities, there's plenty there to play. Two major side-stories bring back some old favourite characters and integrate them well.</p>
<p>Overall, really enjoyed the game and it was perfectly playable on modern hardware. The substories are a bit of a let down but they don't detract from the main game at all. If you're into the Yakuza/Like a Dragon series, don't miss this one.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
