<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>GamertechAU</title>
    <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com" />
    <updated>2025-07-20T18:47:48+10:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>GamertechAU</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.gamertechau.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Animal Shelter 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/animal-shelter-2/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/animal-shelter-2/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/AnimalShelter2.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Simulator"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>
            <category term="#Ad"/>

        <updated>2025-07-20T18:23:57+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/AnimalShelter2.webp" alt="Game poster for Animal Shelter 2 showing a cartoon brown and white husky dog with an orange and white cat peeking out from behind" />
                    Save all the furbabies! Name Animal Shelter 2 Completed on Ongoing Developers&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/AnimalShelter2.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Animal Shelter 2 showing a cartoon brown and white husky dog with an orange and white cat peeking out from behind" /></p>
                <h2>Save all the furbabies!</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: none;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Animal Shelter 2</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Ongoing</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Games Incubator</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Games Incubator, PlayWay S.A.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 data-block-id="a39942f1-c20c-4ed6-ab0f-fda35ed741f1" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Intro</h3>
<p data-block-id="114e2bab-5152-419d-be6b-6007cc61a0cd"><em>Disclaimer: I was provided a free review key from Games Incubator via Keymailer.</em></p>
<p data-block-id="b275bd2d-fdb1-4969-a1c6-c8b95955b70b">Animal Shelter 2 is a fun management simulator game. The player is tasked with renovating an abandoned warehouse and turning it into an animal rescue shelter. You can play either solo or co-op.</p>
<p data-block-id="b275bd2d-fdb1-4969-a1c6-c8b95955b70b">The animals are also extremely cute!</p>
<h3 data-block-id="ea2a89d2-d307-47c0-a1be-ee935c993373">Plot</h3>
<p data-block-id="4fd513f7-b3dc-4c30-9d5b-9f4802e4002c">There's no real story in the game. You start the game having just taken over a decrepit warehouse. Your job is to clean out all the junk, restore it and get to rescuing cats and dogs!</p>
<p data-block-id="7f1311b3-53a3-44ae-8546-fdba480a7518">Send out a car to collect reported strays or abandoned pets. Help the animals settle in and treat behavioural and medical issues. Once they're ready, snap a photo and start looking for their forever home!</p>
<h3 data-block-id="4ad7a67c-6f71-4dca-a7e3-c2c7e606bf9e">Gameplay</h3>
<p data-block-id="8f5944fa-8f2d-431a-a5a9-fc194348551d">Progressing through the tutorials, you unlock a usable workplace. Unlocking cages and enclosed yards to keep the fur-babies safe while letting them play. You can play with them yourself, throwing a ball for the dogs, and handling a laser pointer for cats to chase.</p>
<p data-block-id="c586bda9-5461-4097-b1a7-219326132e13">The animals need pats, play, food &amp; water, comfort items, cleaning and more. They often have specific desires at times, like being held or a selfie. Cats and needy doggos (Frenchies) love to be held in your arms while you walk around the shelter. You can also stick them on a leash and take them to the local park.</p>
<p data-block-id="c586bda9-5461-4097-b1a7-219326132e13">The game also has changing seasons, so the player needs to ensure their areas stay at a comfortable temperature. It gets real cold in winter and they can get sick easily.</p>
<p data-block-id="34e8be88-20de-4601-bea4-2f0556dce110">Ensure you fulfil their needs, complete specific 'breakpoint' tasks that halt their progression and interact with them regularly. If you do, they'll be ready for adoption!</p>
<p data-block-id="fe4e9221-9548-4573-88e3-8e821e0d08ff">When they're ready, take a photo, post an ad and sort through the applicants to find their perfect home. Each animal has behavioural traits that requires specific features to be present at their adoptive home. Conversely, they also have incompatible features they can't stand, or aren't safe with. The player needs to match the pet's desires with the adopter's home and their own desires or the match wont succeed.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/AnimalShelter2Pug-3.webp" alt="Game screenshot showing a pug dressed in a cowboy hat and leather vest" width="1920" height="1080" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/responsive/AnimalShelter2Pug-3-xs.webp 300w ,https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/responsive/AnimalShelter2Pug-3-sm.webp 480w ,https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/responsive/AnimalShelter2Pug-3-md.webp 768w ,https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/55/responsive/AnimalShelter2Pug-3-lg.webp 1024w">
<figcaption >Also you can dress them up...</figcaption>
</figure>
<p data-block-id="e01ad547-61e7-4578-8abd-6b417b290d60">At the end of each day you get reputation based on what you've accomplished. Levels unlock new shelter facilities, upgrades and a wider range of problems faced by the animals. Time progresses as you play, and you'll pass out and wake up next day if you don't manually sleep. Pierre doesn't help himself to your pockets in this one though.</p>
<p data-block-id="5c61d1d4-136c-41da-a5e1-1374f218c6a4">Eventually you get access to a clinic to treat sick animals and isolation to keep contagious pets separate. You need to buy and use testing equipment to diagnose them and sort a treatment plan. There's also an option to outsource to a vet later on.</p>
<p data-block-id="5c61d1d4-136c-41da-a5e1-1374f218c6a4">You can hire staff to take up some of the load maintaining their needs as well as volunteers that help with specific tasks. Staff have different ability levels, controlling the speed and quality of their work. Or if they even notice a task needs doing. Their jobs and priorities are highly configurable.</p>
<p data-block-id="72a17b81-a986-4c54-abb0-2255a58c1874">You also unlock a washing room for dogs to keep them clean while cats need regular brushing. During pre-release, dogs just stood there when being washed. The 1.0 release adds misbehaviour, so dogs will now decide to escape from time to time.</p>
<p data-block-id="6f4f47d5-208f-4aeb-a82a-bc786cfb5c1d">There will also be various missions that pop up. Some need you to drive out yourself and locate an abandoned pet. Others give you promotional opportunities to boost the rep and funding of the shelter.</p>
<h3 data-block-id="6477a8e0-7140-495a-8411-666fde056dc4">Tech</h3>
<p data-block-id="0b45eca5-61d4-4933-804a-ed7489f67c9f">The devs took the time to ensure the game volume wasn't set to 100% by default. As a streamer and headphones wearer, the effort is always greatly appreciated.</p>
<p data-block-id="985aa262-d1d7-4f74-8de4-7e32361f5c9a">The game itself ran well. The audio is chill and fits the game. The graphics are the familiar PlayWay art style, though noticeably improved. The animals have more detailed animations than the humans, as it should be.</p>
<p data-block-id="081ae8a0-8c1a-4172-93f2-76ada0c1c18f">Pre-release, there are some minor animation issues. Placing a pet on the ground can be a bit 'teleporty' sometimes. Filling a water bowl can snap the player's view to level while it fills. A dog chasing the ball can trigger a few rough animations before they chase it.</p>
<p data-block-id="96b00288-7db5-4923-b1ef-11209cd292f7">However the devs are actively updating the game and look to have greatly improved much of it already, ready for release.</p>
<h3 data-block-id="ab37773d-b4da-43da-8b1d-78f9ee1f6b2b">Recommendations</h3>
<p data-block-id="805a75d2-d4b4-4dff-bc9e-87bb2b4c1764">Doggos! Floofs! Play with them all and get that dopamine flowing. If you're into management simulators grab Animal Shelter 2 and support great devs making wholesome games.</p>
<ul>
<li data-block-id="805a75d2-d4b4-4dff-bc9e-87bb2b4c1764"><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2658510/Animal_Shelter_2/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer">Buy Animal Shelter 2 from Steam</a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Duck Detective: The Ghost of Glamping</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-ghost-of-glamping/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-ghost-of-glamping/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/53/DuckDetectiveTheGhostofGlamping.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Point &amp; Click"/>
            <category term="Indie"/>
            <category term="Detective"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-06-20T16:18:15+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/53/DuckDetectiveTheGhostofGlamping.webp" alt="Game poster of Duck Detective: The Ghost of Glamping showing a duck in a brown detective trenchcoat and hat with other animals behind with a green spooky background" />
                    Part two of the engaging ducktective series Name Duck Detective: The Ghost&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/53/DuckDetectiveTheGhostofGlamping.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Duck Detective: The Ghost of Glamping showing a duck in a brown detective trenchcoat and hat with other animals behind with a green spooky background" /></p>
                <h2>Part two of the engaging ducktective series</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Duck Detective: The Ghost of Glamping</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-06-20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Happy Broccoli Games</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Happy Broccoli Games</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Play through</h3>
<p>The brand new release of the Duck Detective series continues the same great story, puzzles and humour. Catch up on <a href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-secret-salami/">the first game here</a></p>
<p>Duck Detective: The Ghost of Glamping begins with our intrepid detective still broke and pining after his ex-wife. To try and break him out of it, his roommate Freddy decides on a fun activity. Glamping! At a haunted sanitorium...</p>
<p>Not like he could say no to Freddy, the Duck Detective soon finds himself at a campsite with mysteries to solve including the identity of Freddy's surprise girlfriend.</p>
<p>Players of the first game will find familiar game mechanics here. The player explores a contained map, interacting with objects and questioning the NPCs to discover key clues. You then combine the clues in your notebook to form a deducktion and quack the case!</p>
<p>Again, Happy Broccoli Games provided a native Linux build of the game alongside their Windows version. Both run extremely well. The art and audio had no issues and suited the game perfectly. Ghost of Glamping also comes with the highest platinum rating on ProtonDB. It doesn't currently have a Steam Deck rating, but the first was Verified so will likely run just fine.</p>
<p>If you liked the first game, or are into fun detective puzzles then definitely grab this series. It also had around 2 hours of content on stream.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Duck Detective: The Secret Salami</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-secret-salami/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-secret-salami/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/52/DuckDetectiveSalami.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Point &amp; Click"/>
            <category term="Indie"/>
            <category term="Detective"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-06-20T15:17:24+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/52/DuckDetectiveSalami.webp" alt="Game poster of Duck Detective The Secret Salami showing a white duck in a detective hat and trenchcoat with assorted animals behind it in a carpark with a building" />
                    A quacking fun detective game Name Duck Detective: The Secret Salami Completed&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/52/DuckDetectiveSalami.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Duck Detective The Secret Salami showing a white duck in a detective hat and trenchcoat with assorted animals behind it in a carpark with a building" /></p>
                <h2>A quacking fun detective game</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Duck Detective: The Secret Salami</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-06-20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Happy Broccoli Games</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Happy Broccoli Games</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Play through</h3>
<p>Duck Detective: The Secret Salami is a simple yet fun and engaging detective story.</p>
<p>The main character Eugene aka the Duck Detective is a broke, freshly-divorced ex-cop. Now a private detective, he's desperate for any job to pay rent. As well as his not-so-secret bread addiction.</p>
<p>Luckily he does manage to land a job investigating a stolen lunch at the office of a bus depot. Fairly quickly though, he realises that there's a lot more going on here than a missing lunch.</p>
<p>The game map is limited to the bus office with several rooms and the surrounding area. The player explores the area interacting with marked objects and questioning characters for key information.</p>
<p>Once you've collected all the information, it's time to make a deducktion. By combining all the info to figure out parts of the story, the player discovers what's really going on and quacks the case!</p>
<p>The game ran smoothly, the audio was spot-on and the art suited the game style well. The devs provided a native Linux version which ran perfectly, though the Windows version also runs well via Proton and a has a platinum rating on ProtonDB. Greatly appreciated!</p>
<p>If you're into fun and relaxed detective games with a bit of humour, I highly recommend looking into the Duck Detective series. The game has around 2 hours of game play. You can find the play through of the <a href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/duck-detective-the-ghost-of-glamping/">second game in the series here</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Black Mesa</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/black-mesa/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/black-mesa/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/51/BlackMesa.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Shooter"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-06-18T16:25:41+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/51/BlackMesa.webp" alt="Game poster for Black Mesa fan remake of Half Life 1" />
                    Worthy remake of Half Life 1 Name Black Mesa Completed on 2025-06-18&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/51/BlackMesa.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Black Mesa fan remake of Half Life 1" /></p>
                <h2 class="align-left">Worthy remake of Half Life 1</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Black Mesa</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">2025-06-18</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Crowbar Collective</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 48.5625px;">
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%; height: 48.5625px;">Crowbar Collective</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Play through</h3>
<p>Having played Half Life 1 &amp; 2 longer ago than I care to remember, it was a fun trip playing this fan-made remake.</p>
<p>In Black Mesa, you play Gordon Freeman, a scientist at the Black Mesa Research Facility. Your sole job seems limited to going into a dangerous area in your hazard suit and pressing a button to start off an experiment on an unknown material.</p>
<p>Doing so however triggers an alien invasion and the player becomes the sole force with any intention of trying to stop it. The other scientists are too scared and the military just wants to "clean" the area of any problems. Including you.</p>
<p>As you play through the game, you collect a wide range of weaponry and equipment. Encounter NPCs that help you progress, deal with hostile forces and discover all the secrets hidden in Black Mesa.</p>
<p>The game also features a large number of puzzles. None of them are particularly complicated, however spotting the things you need to interact with can be difficult as many of them are small or blend into the scenery. There is also a bug since launch in Xen where cables you need to connect are invisible. Reloading a save from before the area generally solves that.</p>
<p>The maps are well made and expansive. The audio worked well, though there were limited voice actors. Progressing through the story and hearing the exact same scientist voices is a little jarring.</p>
<p>The loading times between areas are pretty long, much slower than the original. No issues were encountered however. The game definitely got framey in some of the more open sections. Nothing visibly impacting it, likely shader caching as you move close to new areas. Recommend Windows users to load the game with the DXVK option to get much better performance. Linux users run it with Vulkan by default.</p>
<p>Other than that, the game ran really well with no stability issues. There is also a heap of achievements that are actually achievements. Mostly based around easter eggs throughout the game.</p>
<p>If you enjoyed Half Life back in the day, or into a solid puzzle shooter, then I highly recommend giving it a go.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Kathy Rain: The Director&#x27;s Cut</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/kathy-rain-the-directors-cut/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/kathy-rain-the-directors-cut/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/50/KathyRain1.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Point &amp; Click"/>
            <category term="Detective"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-05-30T16:53:21+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/50/KathyRain1.webp" alt="Game poster of Kathy Rain showing a woman with blue hair sitting on a motorbike lighting a cigarette in front of a diner" />
                    Deep-thinker point-and-click adventure Name Kathy Rain: The Director's Cut Completed on 30-05-2025&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/50/KathyRain1.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster of Kathy Rain showing a woman with blue hair sitting on a motorbike lighting a cigarette in front of a diner" /></p>
                <h2>Deep-thinker point-and-click adventure</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Kathy Rain: The Director's Cut</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">30-05-2025</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Clifftop Games</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Raw Fury</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Play through</h3>
<p>Kathy Rain: The Director's Cut is a rework of the original 2016 game. I decided to play it due to the release of Kathy Rain 2: Soothsayer which caught my eye. Can't jump in halfway through the story!</p>
<p>It's a point-and-click detective game featuring Kathy Rain as the main character. Kathy is a troubled journalist in training with a motorbike who gets dragged back to her home town to discover her family's dark past. The director's cut version adds extra story, more areas to explore, secret achievements and some cosmetic unlocks for your bike.</p>
<p>The point-and-click control mechanics are pretty standard. Move around scenes interacting with objects and questioning other people to build the story and figure out puzzles to advance the story. The puzzles themselves range from more simple ones to brain scorchers which was great as my playing this timed perfectly with me catching the plague...</p>
<p>The story was pretty dark at parts, so keep the mature content warning in mind if you decide to play it. However it was excellently crafted and an enjoyable play through keeping me engaged the whole time. The NPC's you encounter throughout have defined personalities that help build the story well.</p>
<p>Tech-wise the game ran perfectly out of the box. With no graphical, audio or stability issues and has a Platinum rating on ProtonDB. The art style and audio choices worked well with the game and set the mood accurately.</p>
<p>If you're into point-and-click detective adventures, then I highly recommend giving this one a go. Will be playing the second game eventually. One play through on stream took 7.5 hours. There's apparently a lot of optional secrets I missed, so if you're going for a completionist run, expect a fair bit longer.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Yakuza 4 Remastered</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-4-remastered/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/yakuza-4-remastered/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/49/Yakuza4Remastered.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>
            <category term="Beat em Up"/>

        <updated>2025-05-16T15:59:03+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/49/Yakuza4Remastered.webp" alt="Game poster for Yakuza 4 Remastered with 4 men standing in front of a dark street" />
                    Always a good time in Yakuza Name Yakuza 4 Remastered Completed on&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/49/Yakuza4Remastered.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Yakuza 4 Remastered with 4 men standing in front of a dark street" /></p>
                <h2>Always a good time in Yakuza</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Yakuza 4 Remastered</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-05-16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">SEGA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Playthrough</h3>
<p>Continuing on the Yakuza train, Yakuza 4 Remastered was next up.</p>
<p>Ryu Ga Gotoku always craft an epic story and is well worth the experience. Instead of the usual 1-2 main characters, this time they brought 4 to the table. Each of them bring their own story, mini-games and and substories. Their stories are of course all linked and contribute to the greater picture.</p>
<p>Like Yakuza 3, it's a simple remaster and port of the original PS3 game, not a modernised remake like Kiwami 1 &amp; 2. This means it's lacking many quality of life improvements. There's no sprint, in-progress substory locations aren't shown on the map, limited inventory size etc.</p>
<p>The combat is really where you notice the age. Each of the characters have their own style, though they're pretty similar. They also have their own skill tree which is limited compared to modern releases but gives a ton of moves. Heat actions can be difficult to trigger as enemies move before the prompt even appears. The characters attacks and combos tend to have a big delay after they finish, meaning you're standing there unable to dodge or defend yourself a lot.</p>
<p>While Yakuza 3 was known as "Blockuza" due to the majority of the enemies blocking more than attacking, Yakuza 4 features a large amount of stunlocks. Often you get hit once then locked into looped combo attacks and forced to watch as your health evaporates before you can finally dodge away. Staying nimble is recommended.</p>
<p>There's the usual range of mini-games present throughout the game including some new ones. Unfortunately the hostess gameplay is the same from Yakuza 3 which is...not good.</p>
<p>Graphics are upscaled PS3 graphics. Clean and spot on for the Yakuza series. The visual and audio design is excellent as always, perfectly matching the vibe. The game was also stable and ran perfectly with a Platinum rating on ProtonDB.</p>
<p>As always, if you're a fan of the Yakuza/Like a Dragon series, I recommend giving this one a go. While the game shows its age, the story never disappoints. Yakuza 5 Remastered coming soon!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Elroy and the Aliens</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/elroy-and-the-aliens/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/elroy-and-the-aliens/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/48/Elroy_and_the_Aliens.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Point &amp; Click"/>
            <category term="Indie"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-04-07T16:03:16+10:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/48/Elroy_and_the_Aliens.webp" alt="Game poster for Elory and the Aliens showing two people looking at a creature on an engraved rock in front of an alien sky" />
                    A charming point-and-click adventure Name Elroy and the Aliens Completed on 2025-04-07&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/48/Elroy_and_the_Aliens.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Elory and the Aliens showing two people looking at a creature on an engraved rock in front of an alien sky" /></p>
                <h2>A charming point-and-click adventure</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Elroy and the Aliens</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-04-07</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Motiviti</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Motiviti</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Playthrough</h3>
<p>After originally being introduced to Elroy and the Aliens by the developers on Bluesky, I had to play it. Point-and-click adventure games aren't usually my thing (though I have played a fair few), but the game looked fun and the demo cemented it.</p>
<p>In Elroy and the Aliens you play Elroy, a young engineer/inventor and Peggy, an investigative reporter initially there to interview him. After a technical demonstration goes awry, the two begin an adventure that will take them across Earth and beyond to rescue Elroy's long-lost father.</p>
<p>The story and progression is very well done, and the humour throughout is excellent. Some of the steps required to progress took me a little bit, but they're all logical and the game is pretty good at telling you what people need, just need to remember them.</p>
<p>The point-and-click mechanics are the usual system. The player searches scenes for needed items, talks to characters for information and can combine several items to achieve the goal. If you need it, there's a hotkey to highlight areas in the scene you can interact with, though there's an achievement for not using it throughout the play through.</p>
<p>There's a ton of secrets and challenge achievements to unlock, multiple endings and plenty of puzzles to figure out.</p>
<p>The game ran perfectly out of the box with no noticeable bugs and even had a native Linux client which was greatly appreciated. The graphics were excellent, hand-drawn to extremely high detail and the audio was on point.</p>
<p>If you're a fan of point-and-click adventure games this is definitely a game to consider. One ending with definitely not finding all the secrets and achievements took 8.6 hours on stream.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Lost in Play</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/lost-in-play/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/lost-in-play/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/47/LostInPlay.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Point &amp; Click"/>
            <category term="Indie"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-03-31T16:38:35+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/47/LostInPlay.webp" alt="Game poster for Lost in Play showing two children riding a giant beetle in front of a fantasy background" />
                    Engaging puzzle game Name Lost in Play Completed on 2025-03-31 Developers Happy&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/47/LostInPlay.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Lost in Play showing two children riding a giant beetle in front of a fantasy background" /></p>
                <h2>Engaging puzzle game</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Lost in Play</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-03-31</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Happy Juice Games</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Joystick Ventures</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Playthrough</h3>
<p>Been meaning to play this cute little puzzle game for a while now, and glad I did as it was excellent.</p>
<p>Lost in Play is a charming puzzle adventure game where you explore the imaginations of two siblings (Toto and Gal) as they play together, looking for a way back home. During the playthrough you'll encounter many unique characters who all have something to contribute to your adventure.</p>
<p>As you explore different areas, you find objects and how to use them point-and-click adventure style, and complete a large range of wild puzzles and minigames to further the story with plenty of well-done references throughout it.</p>
<p>It's completely family friendly and can be played using a controller, keyboard or mouse for easy preference and accessibility. It can also run on a potato while still having a fantastic and high quality art style.</p>
<p>Lost in Play ran perfectly with no technical issues. One gripe was the settings were inaccessible until you actually started the play through, with volume defaulting to 100%, so its loud with no opportunity to set it to a sane level before the opening cutscene.</p>
<p>Highly recommend giving Lost in Play a go if you're looking for a chill game that's slightly brain-melty. One playthrough took 4.8 hours on stream.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crime Scene Cleaner</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/crime-scene-cleaner/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/crime-scene-cleaner/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/46/Crime-Scene-Cleaner.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Simulator"/>
            <category term="Indie"/>
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-03-28T16:01:04+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/46/Crime-Scene-Cleaner.webp" alt="Game poster for Crime Scene Cleaner showing a man pulling on yellow gloves with cleaning equipment" />
                    Unique job opportunity Name Crime Scene Cleaner Completed on 2025-03-28 Developers President&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/46/Crime-Scene-Cleaner.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Crime Scene Cleaner showing a man pulling on yellow gloves with cleaning equipment" /></p>
                <h2>Unique job opportunity</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Crime Scene Cleaner</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-03-28</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">President Studio</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">President Studio / PlayWay S.A.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Playthrough</h3>
<p>Crime Scene Cleaner is a fun and chill game. You play a father employed as an underpaid high-school janitor who desperately needs an additional income source to pay for his daughters specialist (US) medical bills as the health insurance company sure wont.</p>
<p>Doing a quick job helping out a 'friend' leads to a high-paying but extremely risky career cleaning up crime scenes and destroying evidence for a brutal mob leader. After 'Big Jim' is finished making a mess, your job is to go in, clean up the blood, bullet casings and of course bodies, clean and reposition all the furniture and remove any evidence of criminal activity at the site. Also any valuables as their previous owners no longer need them and you've got bills to pay.</p>
<p>As you progress, you earn skill points to unlock new tools and upgrades. You can leave maps partially completed, however the better the job you do, the more skill points you earn. Each map contains music tapes that unlock an in-game track and multiple secret areas with bonus loot and often an interesting story element. Once a map's completed, you can easily go back and do it again to find missed secrets and benefit from equipment upgrades.</p>
<p>I don't believe there's any failure state for the game as just completing the primary objectives on each map is enough to progress, though you will of course miss the completion bonus.</p>
<p>Tech-wise the game ran perfectly with no graphical, audio or performance issues and has a platinum rating on ProtonDB. The devs also took care of a pet peeve of mine and defaulted the audio to 50%, instead of blasting players with 100% volume which is amazing!</p>
<p>If you're after a chill (and slightly creepy) cleaning sim, I definitely recommend Crime Scene Cleaner. The play through took 11 hours. Also, you can pat the doggo.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Conker&#x27;s Bad Fur Day</title>
        <author>
            <name>GamertechAU</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/conkers-bad-fur-day/"/>
        <id>https://www.gamertechau.com/posts/conkers-bad-fur-day/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/45/conkers-bad-fur-day.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Completed Games"/>

        <updated>2025-03-21T17:06:51+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/45/conkers-bad-fur-day.webp" alt="Game poster for Conker&#x27;s Bad Fur Day showing an animated red squirrel sitting sitting on a red, padded throne drinking milk with a golden crown on his head" />
                    Blast from the past Name Conker's Bad Fur Day Completed on 2025-03-21&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.gamertechau.com/media/posts/45/conkers-bad-fur-day.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Game poster for Conker&#x27;s Bad Fur Day showing an animated red squirrel sitting sitting on a red, padded throne drinking milk with a golden crown on his head" /></p>
                <h2>Blast from the past</h2>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; border-style: hidden;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Name</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Conker's Bad Fur Day</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Completed on</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">2025-03-21</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Developers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Rare</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Publishers</td>
<td style="width: 49.9288%;">Rare</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Playthrough</h3>
<p data-block-id="9d3400dd-af96-4c34-94c3-f3e709e20354" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">I had previously played Conker's Bad Fur Day several times back when the N64 console was new. It was an excellent game back then and the good news is, it's still awesome! After a suggestion from chat, nostalgia kicked in and I immediately added it to the list.</p>
<p data-block-id="97773f9f-2f97-40d7-87f8-bfcb89aaf703" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Conker's BFD is an epic action-adventure/platformer released all the way back in 2001 (feel old yet?) featuring Conker, the red squirrel trying to find his way back home after a blinder down at the pub. Conker inevitably gets waylaid into numerous adventures across different biomes. Each with unique feels and game modes and ends up having one of those days.</p>
<p data-block-id="8c6f4aec-a9ae-4375-aa00-cfe4dade947d" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">The game features many references to popular movies, games and memes of the time. It includes exceptional and often irreverent humour with plenty of well-chosen 4th wall breaks. It also features one of the most enjoyable boss fights in gaming.</p>
<p data-block-id="7c6f12d9-7f71-42af-b794-73d04485a810" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">For this play through I used RetroArch with 8x upscaling. Native 240p N64 resolution doesn't work that well at 1440p, and an Xbox Elite controller. Once tweaked a bit, the game ran smoothly. Though being designed for the N64's single stick controller, it was a bit tricky to handle things like aiming.</p>
<p data-block-id="7c6f12d9-7f71-42af-b794-73d04485a810" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">For those interested in replicating this, ensure you configure at least these settings. Load the game, then press F1 to open settings.</p>
<ul>
<li data-block-id="7c6f12d9-7f71-42af-b794-73d04485a810" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Core Options/RDP Plugin: ParaLLEl-RDP</li>
<li data-block-id="7c6f12d9-7f71-42af-b794-73d04485a810" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Core Options/ParaLLEl-RDP/Upscaling factor: 8x</li>
<li data-block-id="7c6f12d9-7f71-42af-b794-73d04485a810" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Core Options/Framerate: Fullspeed</li>
</ul>
<p>Reload the game and enjoy the fast and smooth Conker.</p>
<p data-block-id="00c7d6c3-31c8-45ae-9f11-e2ef66a97a7b" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">The audio was excellent and the graphics are reminiscent of Rare's other games such as Banjo-Kazooie. It stuttered a fair bit on RetroArch's default settings, but giving it a bit more made it run great.</p>
<p data-block-id="33514cf0-655d-455a-8f54-2c6bda61879e" data-pm-slice="1 1 []">Conker's Bad Fur Day is definitely a brilliant game, well worth a play through and I enjoyed going back to it. On stream it took ~12.5 hours.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
